we all know that digital computers
change virtually every aspect of our
life
well the arrival of quantum computers
could be even more historic than that
we're now on the initial stages of the
next Revolution we're talking about a
new generation of computers the ultimate
computer a computer that computes an
atoms the ultimate constituents of
matter itself
the question is who's involved in this
race to perfect quantum computers and
the answer is everyone
all the big players are part of this
race because if they're not Silicon
Valley could become the next Rust Belt
also anyone who's interested in security
is interested in the quantum computers
they can crack almost any code that is
based on digital technology that's why
the FBI the CIA and all national
governments are following this very
closely
Quantic computers will change everything
the economy how we solve problems the
way we interact with the universe you
name it quantum computers will be there
I'm Dr Michio okaku professor of
theoretical physics at the City
University of New York and author of
quantum Supremacy about the rise of
quantum computers
[Music]
you see computers have gone through
three basic stages
stage one was the analog computer so two
thousand years ago there was a shipwreck
and in the boat that sank was a device
and when you brushed away the dirt and
debris you begin to realize that it was
a machine a machine of incredible
complexity it was in fact the world's
first analog computer and it was
designed to map the motion of the Moon
the sun and the planets to simulate the
universe but as we primitive peoples
became more prosperous we had to count
things count how many cows you had count
how much profit you made
analog computers could be based on
sticks bones whatever it took to count
so this went on for thousands of years
until finally we reached the work of
Charles Babbage
he creates the ultimate analog computer
with hundreds of gears and levers and
pulleys and by turning the crank you
could then calculate longitude latitude
you can calculate interest rates it was
very valuable to have an instrument like
that for the banking industry for
Commerce
[Music]
then World War II comes along babbage's
machine is simply too primitive to break
the German code so the job was given to
mathematicians like Alan Turing
Alan Turing was the one who codified a
lot of the laws of computation into what
is called a turing machine and of course
is digital
now the digital Revolution is based on
transistors it operates on zeros and
ones zeros and ones at the speed of
electricity every digital computer is a
turning machine
The Next Step Beyond digital computers
is the Quantum era Richard Feynman was
one of the founders of quantum
electrodynamics but also a Visionary and
he asked himself a simple question how
small can you make a transistor and he
realized that the ultimate transistor is
an atom one atom that could control the
flow of electricity not just on or off
but everything in between we have to go
to quantum computers
computers that compute on atoms rather
than on transistors
transistors are based on zeros and one
zeros and one reality is not reality is
based on electrons and particles and
these particles in turn act like waves
so you have to have a new set of
mathematics to discuss the waves that
make up a molecule and that's where
quantum computers come in
they're based on electrons and these
electrons how come they have so much
computational power because they could
be in two places at the same time that's
what gives quantum computers their power
they compute
on not just one universe but an infinite
number of parallel universes
at the fundamental level quantum
mechanics can be reduced down to a cat
Schrodinger's cat
let's take a box
in the Box you put a cat and the
question is is the cat dead or alive
well until you open the box you don't
know
it is alive and dead simultaneously it's
in a superposition of two states
in other words the universe has split in
half
in one half the cat is alive in the
other Universe the cat is Dead That's
the basis of the quantum theory that
until you make a measurement the cat can
exist in both States simultaneously in
fact in any number of states
simultaneously
the cat could be Dead Alive playing
jumping sideways sick any number of
states now why am I mentioning this
because this summarizes the power of
quantum computers
quantum computers compute unparalleled
universes
that's why they are so powerful
[Music]
so how much faster is a quantum computer
over a digital computer in principle
infinitely faster
when we talk about digital computers we
can measure their power in terms of bits
for example spin up spin down zeros and
one would constitute one bit for a large
digital computer we're not talking about
billions of bits that are modeled by
transistors
except now quantum computers talk not
just about spin up or spin down but
everything in between that's called a
qubit one qubit represents all the
possibilities of an object spinning
between up and down
thousands of qubits can now be modeled
with the latest generation of quantum
computers eventually we hope to hit a
million
and so we're talking about exceeding the
power of ordinary digital computers
that's called Quantum Supremacy it is
the point at which a quantum computer
can outrace and outperform a digital
computer on a certain task
we passed that several years ago but we
want a machine that could exceed the
power of any digital computer we're not
there yet but we're very close to it
the number one problem facing quantum
computers is the question of the
coherence
everything is based on particles like
electrons and electrons have waves
associated with them
when these waves are vibrating in unison
it's called coherence
and then you can do calculations of a
quantum mechanical nature but if you
fall out of coherence
then everything vibrates at a different
frequency and what is that called noise
you have to reduce the temperature down
to near absolute zero
so everything is pretty much vibrating
slowly in unison that's difficult
now nature solves this problem
it is the basis of all life on the earth
photosynthesis for example is a quantum
mechanical process Mother Nature
can create coherence at room temperature
amazing a flower can do calculations
that are most advanced Quantum a
computer cannot
Mother Nature is still smarter than us
when it comes to the quantum theory
so let's face it there are hurdles
affecting the growth of quantum
computers but they pale in comparison to
the benefits that may be Unleashed by
quantum computers we're talking about
opening the floodgates
take a look for example of food supply
the Green Revolution that allows us to
feed the population of the world is
slowly coming to an end we're trying to
use quantum computers to unlock the
secret of how to make fertilizer from
nitrogen take a look at energy
quantum computers may be able to create
fusion power by stabilizing the super
hot hydrogen inside a fusion reactor and
take a look at medicine you realize that
life is based on molecules molecules
that can create Alzheimer's disease
Parkinson's disease cancer
these diseases are beyond the reach of
digital computers but hey this is what
quantum computers do we'll be able to
model diseases at the molecular level
and that's why we hope to cure the
incurable using quantum computers we're
talking about turning medicine upside
down
my personal hope for quantum computers
is that we'll be able to create a theory
of the entire universe the theory that
eluded Einstein the theory that would
explain black holes and supernovas and
Galactic Evolution but the equations are
so complex that no one no one has been
able to solve them perhaps they'll be
solved in the memory of a quantum
computer
foreign
to learn even more from the world's
biggest thinkers get big think Plus for
your business