a poncho from a wooden indian
[Music]
let's get you comfy
you happy now
freeze don't
move you got me
nice potato gun barrel's a little long
between that and the wide gauge it's
gonna diminish your fps
and now you're out of ammo what's that
thing on your chest
it's a uh electromagnet you should know
i've got a box of them right here
what does a power
oh my god
that
that's is that iron man technically i am
technically you're dead
yeah what point what happened to him
life
i built him i take care of him
i'll fix him like a mechanic yeah
if i was building iron man and war
machine sign patriot now
that's way cooler no time anyways
i would have added in um the retro
retro reflective panel to make him
stealth mode you want a stealth mode
cool right
that's actually a good idea maybe i'll
build one
not a good idea what are you doing i'm
gonna break his finger
he's in pain he's been injured leave him
alone sorry
are you don't worry about it i'll fix it
so uh who's home well my mom already
left for the diner and
dad went to 7-eleven to get scratchers i
i guess he won because that was six
years ago
which happens dad's leave no need to be
a [ __ ] about it here's what i need
a laptop a digital watch a cell phone
the pneumatic actuator from your bazooka
over there
map of town a big spring and a tuna fish
sandwich
what's in it for me salvation what's his
name
who the kid that bullies you at school
what's his name how do you know that
i got just the thing
this is a pinata for a cricket
i'm kidding it's a very powerful weapon
pointed away from your face
press the button on top it discourages
bullying
non-lethal just to cover one's ass deal
deal what do you say deal deal
what's your name harley and you're
the mechanic tony
you know what keeps going through my
head where's my sandwich
you