See, what do the
really wealthy, really smart people
know?
They know what they want to do
with their time.
But why there are certain
people who are able to make wealth
and certain people who are not wealthy?
I was reading on your website, the
first thing it says that 50,000 crore managed
in the past.
I was in a
business where I would sit across
the table from some of the
wealthiest folks in India.
Okay.
And talk to them about how to
manage their money.
Help them with that.
You would meet people who
had 25 crores, 30 crores.
And then you suddenly start feeling
that money is available.
Like there is enough money to go
around.
It's just that it is
concentrated in the hands of a
few people.
Like India has one of the craziest Gini
coefficients, which is the wealth
inequality thing, right?